We need to have a serious talk about a
problem that I see so many coaches have.
It's the number one thing again that
stops them from being successful. And
I've been talking about this on my page
for a long time.
But when I work with coaches, it's
literally the thing the biggest thing
that stops them from having the kind of
success that they want in their
business. It's perfectionism.
And you might not think you suffer with
perfectionism that you deal with it.
Here's how I define it. Anything that's
stopping you from putting yourself out
there without it being dialed in perfect
or whatever it is, anything that gives
you pause because you're unsure, is it
going to be good enough? That's where
perfectionism comes in because we are
either trying to control the perception
that people have of us or we're trying
to avoid feeling like we're not doing
good enough. If we're trying to control
the outcome so much, because we are
concerned that it's not going to produce
the best result unless it's perfect.
And that's the biggest reason why I see
coaches and mentors not actually
reaching their goals. It's the number
one thing that has stopped me and paused
me and put the stop sign on myself
reaching my own goals throughout the
years is because I know how to do things
really well. I have a spirit of
excellence. I know what produces the
best results and I let that get into my
head to stop me from showing up
effectively to reach people. It happens
all the time. Even a video like this the
last 3 days. Now granted, I had a a
cold. I had a head cold. My I had a
stuffy nose. This is like the last day
of it. You can barely hear it. But I
could not come up with what I wanted to
talk about in a video like this for the
last 3 days. And I didn't record a video
for YouTube. I try to do at least one to
two videos a week. And I let
perfectionism of, well, is it the
perfect video? Is it the perfect topic?
Is that I let that get in the way of me
even recording anything or putting it
out there.
We all experience this. What produces
results in your business is not being
perfect. Rather, it's being consistent.
Rather, it's showing up. Rather, it's
being authentic and also being
confident, having the confidence. That's
one of the biggest things I think as
well is having the confidence to show up
and to know, listen, whatever happens
happens. Whatever people think about
this, it does not matter. And what I
have found is that when I have that
attitude, it produces far better results
financially in the tune of producing
multiple eight figures in business to
the tune of producing better financial
results than I ever wanted to, not
waiting for the perfect moment or the
perfect outcome.
We see this so often. People don't put
their lead magnet out there. They don't
run their ads. This can happen if you're
trading stocks. you're worried about
getting the perfect entry. This and and
we even attach an identity of well, I'm
responsible to make sure that I do the
right thing. The need to do the right
thing all the time is the biggest
greatest factor that prevents people
from reaching their financial goals on
the internet, online, from being able to
create the kind of life, business, and
family that they want. It really is. I'm
not telling you to go out there and be
flippant and reckless and make stupid
mistakes that you know better about.
What I'm telling you is to stop worrying
so much about getting every little
detail perfect. I found that in my
family life that I became so nervous and
worried about always making sure that my
wife was happy and that I was doing
everything perfect in my marriage that I
literally started walking on eggshells.
Not because that she was making me do
that. By the way, she is the last person
in the world that would make me do that.
Because I was holding myself to an
unreasonable standard of perfection
that came in because I felt afraid that
if I was not perfect, what that would
mean about me, if I did not have the
perfect results.
And I'll tell you that when we attach
our identity to everything going
perfect,
we will consistently have things
go wrong for us. Our nervous system will
be so locked into
this state of
chaos, nervous energy,
a lack of peace.
Do your best. Optimize things. I'm all
for optimization.
I'm all for improvement.
I think we can all improve. But waiting
to be perfect before you put stuff out
there. Waiting to be perfect before you
show up in your life, in your business,
is just not going to produce the results
that you want. I get that. That might be
your personality. Can I tell you this?
Do it. Do it where you feel you need to,
but not in your business.
That's all I'm saying. And I would
encourage you to try not letting like
like what if you recorded a video and
you had
a messy background behind you. Or what
if you recorded a video and you
stuttered a little bit at the beginning?
Or what if you recorded a video and you
didn't have the perfect topic that was
going to produce the ultimate financial
result that you thought of overall, but
maybe it was some good nurture content
to connect with people and actually
realizing the value of nurture content.
And why we produce nurture content is to
make that connection.
No, instead we end up waiting until we
have the perfect strategy, the perfect
feeling like internally, okay, I know
now this is going to work. Can I tell
you every time that I was always like, I
know this is going to work. It almost
always never does. And it's not because
I suck at determining is stuff going to
work or not. No, I've been in this
industry of marketing online for over 22
years. I know what works and I know what
doesn't. But everything is still a test
and an experiment to optimize and see
okay is this going to produce that
result. We have certain parameters
things that we've tested and evidence.
But at the same time we're I'm surprised
all the time. And so again when you can
learn to calm your nervous system down
when you can learn to
not let that need for it all to be
perfect. Rather you focus on let me take
imperfect action. Let me make
imperfection
part of my personality. And you
literally shift into that place where
you embrace imperfection
in everything that you're doing. You
start to embrace taking action before
it's all perfect.
You start to embrace putting yourself
out there before it's all perfect.
And you give up this this
version of yourself that always does
everything perfect as this identity that
you must do
and you relax just a little bit and you
let loose just a little bit and you go
against what might be normal in this
area for you. It might feel weird. It
might feel like you're doing the wrong
thing,
but it's actually the most authentic and
right thing that you can do. It's the
way that you show up that's effective.
It's the way that you can reach people
with your message better. It's the way
that you can communicate better. It's
the way that you can start to
truly love and enjoy doing the hard
things. Because when we operate and do
the hard things in our business through
perfectionism,
we end up stalling ourselves far often
than reaching our results. If you're
wondering why everything feels like it's
two steps forward, five steps backward.
Perfectionism is one of the biggest
reasons why that is.
The need for things to be perfect. The
need for it to get right. and need I
just I need it to produce a result and
not or else I'm not going to do it. What
I don't want to waste my I hear people I
don't want to waste my time putting
stuff out there that I'm not sure is
going to produce a result. That's a real
fancy pretty way
of packaging perfectionism.
Well, I don't want to waste my time. I
don't want to be unwise
by doing like I hear the the thousands
of different versions of the ways that
people package perfectionism
and none of them is better than the
other.
None of them is wisdom. Take it from me
as somebody who has built online
businesses,
made multiple millions of dollars
online, and I've seen what works and
I've seen what doesn't. And
perfectionism
is the biggest thing that stops people.
It's the biggest thing. If they can
literally just tweak that and start to
like let loose and be a little bit wild
and free
and start to experience the fun and
excitement and that childlike, let's
just put it out there and have fun with
it. And they learn to guide their
nervous system to enjoy doing that.
and they stop waiting until they finally
arrive at some moment where it's all
ready and they finally feel ready to do
everything. I I remember I used to hear
people say, "I'm just getting the
foundation set up. I'm just getting the
foundation set up." And they were
getting the foundation set up in their
business to make sure that things would
go perfectly for 10 years without ever
doing anything. And I see people that do
this and then they blame coaches, they
blame mentors, they blame everything
around them in their life for why
they're not reaching their goals.
Because if they now have something to
blame now, they now they give up
responsibility for the fact that well, I
didn't take action because it wasn't
good enough yet because I have such a
standard. I have such a high standard of
excellence. these high standards
of performance is why I haven't done it
yet.
When it's really just pride and ego and
perfectionism all wrapped up in some
pretty little package
that is never going to produce the
result they're looking for.
It's not. It's especially not in
business. Business it it might work in
other parts of your life. I I'm going to
I'm just going to give you that. All
right? It might,
you know, doesn't work for me. It might
for you, but I will tell you in
business,
it will spit you out and run you ragged
trying to be perfect.
And so, you will sooner reach your
result, your results that you want. You
will get the results that you want, that
you have been hoping for, that you've
been praying for, that you've been
wanting in your business when you start
to give up perfectionism.
I promise you that. Listen, if you're a
coach, mentor, trainer, consultant,
service provider, and you want to know
how do I grow my business? What's the
stuff to actually do? What's the
strategy? What's the sauce, Jeremiah,
that actually works? Jump in my Wealthy
Coach Academy program. Click one of the
links in the description of this video
below and I will walk you through how to
get started, how to jump in, how to
join, and how to work with me to help
you achieve the dream that you've always
wanted in your business. We'll talk soon
everybody. Share this video. Have a good
one.